# **ARCHANA H NAIR**

**(** + 45 71451513

□ archana.harinair@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/archana-h-nair-0b64992a/

github.com/archana6832

archana6832.github.io/portfolio-website/

O Copenhagen , Denmark

**SUMMARY** 

Full stack web developer with a background in Engineering teaching and mentoring. Experienced in mentoring more than 15 groups of students in their Engineering final year projects and teaching more than 500 students throughout the career. Competent in creating websites and applications from concept, layout and interactive elements to server-side and databases. Skilled in the latest practices in web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS).

### **SKILLS**

#### Front End Development

- -HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- -Libraries / Frameworks (React, Redux, Angular, Material, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS, ¡Query)
- -Responsive design, modals and touch interaction
- -AJAX & JSON
- -Version Control (Git)
- -unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing)
- -Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)

#### **Back End Development**

- -NodeJS & Express
- -APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- -Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Firestore, Heroku, Netlify)
- -Relational & non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

#### **EDUCATION**

#### CareerFoundry

Full-Stack Development Program April 2021 - Feb 2022 <u>View Program</u>

#### Speak -School of Danish

Danish Language Leanring
June 2018 - Dec 2019
B2 -Advanced Level

# T K M College Of Engineering

Masters in Engineering & Technology August 2012 - Oct 2014 Second Rank in University

### T K M College Of Engineering

Bachelors in Engineering &Technology August 2001 - May 2005

### WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

## CareerFoundry Project- Meet app (Jan 2022)

- Developed a progressive-web application with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique with Enzyme and Jest.
- Translated user stories into scenarios for unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing (Cucumber) and end-to-end testing(Puppeteer)
- Implemented serverless functions with AWS lambda to authenticate and authorize users. **GitHub Repo**

### CareerFoundry Project - Chat App (Feb 2022)

- Developed a chat app for mobile devices using React Native.
- Used Gifted Chat library to create the chat interface and its functionality and Android Studio's Virtual Device to manually view and test the app.
- Used Google Firestore Database to store chat conversations and Google Firebase authentication to authenticate users anonymously.
   GitHub Repo

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Managing Partner Jan 2015 - Feb 2018 Fashion Jewellers and Textiles

- Managed day to day operations of the store.
- Achieved better customer satisfaction by maintaining trendy collections.
- Assured better customer satisfaction by listening to customers and implementing their suggestions.

# **Assistant Professor** May 2010 - Nov 2011 **Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai, India**

- Mentored students in their projects and ensured the submission on time.
- Assisted Head of Department, achieved better performance of students by introducing new teaching plan.
- Planned teaching methodologies effectively and assured 85% passing yearly.